A Guide to the Papers Compiled by Raymond Gorges for a Book on the Gorges Family, 1616-1940
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers Compiled by Raymond Gorges for a Book on the Gorges Family 1616-1940
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1641
This collection consists of ca. 5,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was made a gift to the Library from Mrs. Grace Vernon Gorges of Newport, Rhode Island, on April 19, 1943.
Scope and Content Information
The Gorges family papers consist of ca. 5,000 items, 1616-1940, and contain the material used by Raymond Gorges to write his book, The Story of a Family through Eleven Centuries, History of the Gorges Family. The book provides an excellent guide to the materials; the items have been identified according to Mr. Gorges and left in the order used by him with slight modifications. The papers include genealogy information that Mr. Gorges used to produce his pedigree located at the end of the book. There are also family histories, beginning in 1066 when the family was in France; and individual biographies. This material contains information on the careers and schooling of family members as well as copies of their correspondence. The legal papers are an excellent source of English documents and provide added information on the family's interesting and noble history. Also provided is historical information used to provide background for Mr. Gorges' book. Included are Mr. Gorges' research notes which give some indication of his organization for the book. Altough he failed to publish it in his lifetime, his wife had the book published to his specifications. There are also postcards of country scenes in England and Ireland. The materials deal with the entire history of the family from 1066 to the 20th Century but original documents date from 1618. Also included is Mr. Gorges' personal correspondence about his research; this correspondence is interfiled with relevant materials. This is an excellent collection for historical information on England and Ireland especially the historical intertwining of the two nations.
Contents List
- Arms
  - Designs of the Arms of Sir Edward Gorge of Wrakefallin, Somersetshire 1568 (Box 1)
  - Designs of the Arms of the Butshead Branch of Sir Arthur and Sir Edward 1576-1655 (Box 1)
  - Designs of the Family Arms in Ireland 1600-1900s (Box 1)
  - Designs of the Arms of Dame Anne 1620 (Box 1)
  - Designs of the Gorges Family Arms 1625, 1643 (Box 1)
  - Designs of the Gorges Family Arms n.d., (3 Folders) (Box 1)
- Pedigrees
  - Smaller Pedigrees in the Making 1066-1900s (Box 1)
  - John Russell Pedigree 1205-1227 (Box 1)
  - Russell Pedigree 1212-1571 (Box 1)
  - Early Gorges' Pedigree 1230-1400 (Box 1)
  - Pedigree Material for Tamerton Foliot 1236-1461 (Box 1)
  - Demoreville Family Pedigree 1381, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Chancery Requestsand Proceedings 1386-1780 (Box 1)
  - Hamilton Pedigree 1410-1727 (Box 1)
  - Pedigrees 1419-1854 (Box 1)
  - Genealogical Charts from the Papers of Rev. Frederick Brown n.d. (Box 1)
  - Gorges Pedigrees n.d. (Box 1)
  - Kelly and O'Kelly, Chart Pedigree and Notes on Pedigree n.d. (Box 1)
  - Loftus Pedigree 1561-1903 (Box 2)
  - Pedigree of the Gorges of Kilbrew, County Meath 1561-1900s (Box 2)
  - Howard Pedigree 1577-1906 (Box 2)
  - Pedigree in Lansdowne Manuscripts-Descendants of Sir Thomas 1600-1700 (Box 2)
  - Descendants of Sir Arthur and Lady Gorges 1700-1800 (Box 2)
  - Gorges' Pedigree 1712, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Hamilton Gorges' Pedigree 1839-1860 (Box 2)
- Family Histories
  - Photostat Negatives of Brown Manuscripts 1066-1384, (3 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Notes on the Gorges Family 1066-1781 (Box 2)
  - Early History, v. 1-4 1236-1609 (Box 2)
  - "Diggings" 1421-1801, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Copy of Early Manuscript on the Gorges Family n.d (Box 2)
  - List of Abbreviations n.d. (Box 2)
  - M.S. Rawl n.d. (Box 2)
  - Early History, v. 5-12 1534-1717 (Box 3)
  - Notes on Members of the Gorges Family 1547-1680 (Box 3)
  - Copy of first tryout by the Rev. F. Brown 1869, 1875, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Directions and Letters regarding the Rev. F. Brown and the Gorges Family History 1921-1924, n.d. (Box 3)
- Individual Histories
  - Materials Ante 1200 (Box 3)
  - Sir Ralph Russell and Sons 1226-1291 (Box 3)
  - Sir Thomas de Gorges 1236-1266 (Box 3)
  - Gorges of Tamerton Foliot and Shipton Gorges 1241-1346 (Box 3)
  - Unidentified Persons 1255-1667 (Box 3)
  - Ralph de Gorges 1272 (Box 3)
  - Daughters n.d. (Box 3)
  - Thomas Gorges n.d. (Box 3)
  - Unknown Family Members n.d. (Box 3)
  - The Gorges of Budockshed 1272-1870 (Box 4)
  - Sir Ralph de Gorges, King's Army in Gascony 1297 (Box 4)
  - Sir Ralph de Gorges 1306-1323 (Box 4)
  - Theobald Russell et al. 1311, 1316, 1340 (Box 4)
  - Gradual Extiction of the Male Line 1339-1937 (Box 4)
  - Tamerton Foliot Branch of the Gorges Family 1369-1434 (Box 4)
  - Sir Morys Russell and Heirs 1376, 1416 (Box 4)
  - Sir Theobald et al 1380-1421 (Box 4)
  - Sir Theobald Gorges 1401(1428-1453)1470 (Box 4)
  - Sir Thomas Beauchamp et al 1419 (Box 4)
  - Sir Thibault de Gorges et al 1423-1616 (Box 4)
  - Sir William Gorges et al 1499-1625 (Box 5)
  - Sir Edmund Gorges et al 1511-1610 (Box 5)
  - Helena Snakenborg (Marchioness of Northampton) 1549-1635 (Box 5)
  - Tristram and his son William Gorges 1551-1627 (Box 5)
  - Edmund Gorges and Anne Walsh 1558-1574 (Box 5)
  - Sir Edward Gorges 1558-1625 (Box 5)
  - Edward, Lord Gorges 1564-1624 (Box 5)
  - Sir Ferdinando Gorges and Descendants 1564-1624 (Box 5)
  - Roger Budshed and Budshed Manor 1576 (Box 5)
  - Sir Arthur Gorges 1580-1625 (Box 6)
  - Sir Theobald Gorges of Ashley, Wiltshire, England 1583-1687 (Box 6)
  - Lady Bridget Philip 1584- (Box 6)
  - Jane, Lady Gorges 1585-1665 (Box 6)
  - William Gorges of Alderyton (Jr.) 1589 (Box 6)
  - Nicholas Gorges 1594 (Box 6)
  - Signature of Sir Ferdinando Gorges 1597 (Box 6)
  - Sir Robert Gorges 1598-1636 (Box 6)
  - Thomas Gorges, D.D. 1603-1668 (Box 6)
  - Sir Thomas Gorges et al 1609 (Box 6)
  - Richard, Lord Gorges 1619-1676(?) (Box 6)
  - Col. John Gorges 1620-1680 (Box 6)
  - Elizabeth, Lady Smyth 1627 (Box 6)
  - Judge Samuel Gorges 1635-1686 (Box 6)
  - Kilbrew Line of Dr. Robert Gorges, L.L.D and Jane Loftus Ante 1648-1700 (Box 6)
  - Robert Gorges of Batcombe 1649 (Box 6)
  - Fernando Gorges 1658, 1659 (Box 6)
  - Kilbrew Line of Lieut. Gen. Richard Gorges 1662-1728 (Box 6)
  - Col. Thomas Gorges 1670 (Box 6)
  - Diary of Mrs. Elizabeth Treke (connection unknown) 1671-1710 (Box 7)
  - 1696 (Box 7)
  - Ferdinando Gorges of Eye 1701 (Box 7)
  - Kilbrew Line of Richard Gorges 1743-1821 (Box 7)
  - Thomas Bomford 1758 (Box 7)
  - George Edmund Howard 1786 (Box 7)
  - Hamilton Gorges 1802 (Box 7)
  - Dean Robert George Gorges 1804 (Box 7)
  - Edmond Howard Gorges 1810- (Box 7)
  - Capt. John Howard Gorges 1820-1903 (Box 7)
  - John Howard Gorges and Frances Richards 1826 (Box 7)
  - Hamilton Gorges 1860 (Box 7)
  - Sir Edmund Gorges 1872-1924 (Box 7)
  - Sir Howard Gorges 1872-1924 (Box 7)
  - Raymond Gorges 1877-1943 (Box 7)
  - Mary Gorges 1885, 1912, (2 Folders) (Box 7)
  - Mary Gorges 1911 (Box 7)
- Family Careers and Schooling:
  - Advowsons 1236-1574 (Box 7)
  - Careers and Schooling 1242-1316 (Box 7)
  - Military Service 1257-1323 (Box 7)
  - Public Service and Education 1265-1802 (Box 7)
  - Literary Works 1879-1911 (Box 7)
- Correspondence
  - Photostat of Princess Eleanor's Letter Ante 1500 (Box 8)
  - Edward Gorges and Richard Gorges 1602-1706 (Box 8)
  - Helena Marchinoness of Northhampton, Katherine Gorges, Tibbot Gorges, Richard Gorges, Eliza Smyth, Elizabeth Gorges, Thomas Smyth, Hugh Smyth, Edward Gorges, Ferdinando Gorges, William Gorges, copies of originals 1608-1685, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Photostats of some of the letters in the previous folder 1608-1658 (Box 8)
  - Copies of Sir Ferdinando Gorges and Eliza Gorges' Letters 1622-1637 (Box 8)
  - Photostats of Sir Ferdinando's letters 1623-1637 (Box 8)
  - Sir Edward Gorges, typed copies of originals 1623-1737 (Box 8)
  - Sir Robert Gorges, typed copies of originals 1658-1693 (Box 8)
  - Lucy Gorges, Lady Howth to Dean Swift, typed copies of the orginals 1734-1737 (Box 8)
  - Unknown Correspondence, original 1783 Apr 5 (Box 8)
  - Power Tuam, John Coshow, Hester Lindsay, Oliver Bowen, Lucy King, Lucy Ducker, Lord Halifax to members of the Gorges Family, mostly originals 1800-1900 (Box 8)
  - Family correspondence from Thomas Young, John Wilson to various members of the family including Hamilton Gorges 1836, 1844, 1847 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence to Raymond Gorges about the writing and research for The Story of a Family through Eleven Centuries1921, 1925 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence to Raymond Gorges, originals 1930-1940 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence to Raymond Gorges, originals 1936-1937 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence to Raymond Gorges, originals 1938-1939 (Box 8)
  - Unknown Correspondence, original 1944 (Box 8)
  - Handwriting Sample of Jane French n.d. (Box 8)
  - Hamilton Gorges n.d. (Box 8)
- Family Legal Information
  - Kilmoon Estates
    - Copy of Indenture on Kilmoon 1614- (Box 8)
    - Case of the Manor of Kilmoon 1614 (Box 8)
    - Legal Documents pertaining to Kilmoon in Latin 1621 (Box 8)
    - Recollections of Kilmoon 1664-1763 (Box 8)
    - Estate Information 1693 (Box 8)
    - Estate Administration 1723-1761 (Box 8)
    - Estate Administration 1734-1761 (Box 8)
    - Estate Information 1761 (Box 9)
    - Customs Abstract 1761 (Box 9)
    - Estate Information 1779 (Box 9)
    - Estate Court Rolls 1779-1832 (Box 9)
    - Estate Given to Hamilton Gorges 1822 Nov 29 (Box 9)
    - Draft of Surrender 1823 May 6 (Box 9)
  - Kilbrew Estate
    - Entail of Kilbrew 1830 (Box 9)
    - Kilbrew and Other Estates, Balance Sheets 1920-1921 (Box 9)
    - Estate Information n.d., (4 Folders) (Box 9)
  - Gorges' Estates, General
    - Receipts 1913, 1921 (Box 9)
    - Balance Sheets 1921 (Box 9)
  - Webster Estate
    - Instructions to Counsel 1863-1912 (Box 9)
    - Land Commission Documents 1903-1925, n.d. (Box 9)
    - Rulings on Title 1911, n.d. (Box 9)
    - Release on Title and other documents 1912-1926 (Box 9)
    - Dunshauglin 1913 (Box 9)
    - Balance Sheets 1922-1925 (Box 9)
- Indentures
  - Gorges E. Howard to Robert Moorehouse 1762 (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges Jr. and Robert Y. French 1832 Nov 27 (Box 10)
  - Mortgages 1842 Jun 1 (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges and the French Family 1851 Oct 18 (Box 10)
  - Miss Susan L. Gorges 1861 Apr 4 (Box 10)
  - Websters to Loudon 1875 Sep 30 (Box 10)
  - Primatestown Estate 1875 Sep 30 (Box 10)
  - Pelch et al to I.C.G. Egerton 1891 (Box 10)
- Marriage Settlements
  - Hamilton Gorges to Miss Howard 1768 (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges to Alicia French 1797 (Box 10)
  - John Gorges to Frances Richards 1808 (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges to Gertrude Frances Bennet 1839, (3 Folders) (Box 10)
  - French Family 1844 (Box 10)
  - Memorium of the Marriage between Hamilton Gorges and Miss Bennet 1860 (Box 10)
  - John, Lord de Freyne to Miss Mary Kelly 1863 (Box 10)
  - Marriage Settlement Documents 1880 (Box 10)
- Legal Cases
  - Barnewells 1666 Jun 25 (Box 10)
  - Advowsons 1731 (Box 10)
  - Copyhold Tenures 1747 May 16 (Box 10)
  - Mr. Gorges 1797 Apr 22 (Box 10)
  - Charleville v. Hamilton Gorges 1802 (Box 10)
  - Gorges v. Armstrong 1802 (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges 1819 (Box 10)
  - Sir Henry Meredyth 1830 (Box 10)
  - Robert French, Esq. 1832 Jul 9 (Box 10)
  - Frances Gorges 1838 (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges 184_ (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges n.d. (Box 10)
  - Hamilton Gorges 1844 (Box 11)
  - Margaret Dignan v. Hamilton Gorges 1844-1860 (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Gorges 1846 (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Gorges-opinion 1857 (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Gorges 1860-1861 (Box 11)
  - William Daniel Kelly v. John Darcy et al 1872 (Box 11)
  - Court Records for Maine 1927 (Box 11)
- Deeds
  - Estate Deeds 1676-1695 (Box 11)
  - Richard Finn 1734 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Recovery for Meath Estate 1743 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Release 1758 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Assignment,Bomford and Gorges 1761 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Annuity, Hamilton Gorges to Jane Gorges 1784 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Annuity 1784 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Annuity, Hamilton Gorges to Gorges Edmund Howard 1797 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Annuity, Hamilton Gorges to Thomas Glasco 1797 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Assignment between Hamilton Gorges and Micheal Chester 1800 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Assignment between Richard French, Hamilton Gorges, and Richard French 1810 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Settlement 1830 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Mortgage 1832 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Assignment, Hamilton Gorges 1836 (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Gorges to John Spear 1850 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Assignment, The Gorges Family 1858 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Appointment 1858 (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Gorges to H.M. and F. French 1858 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Enfranchisement 1861 (Box 11)
  - Deed of Settlement, Miss E.G. Gorges and H.B. Webster to Trustees 1863 (Box 11)
  - Hereford Deeds 1900- (Box 11)
  - Deed Sales 1930 (Box 11)
- Bonds
  - H. Gorges to C. Ward 1840 (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Gorges 1851 (Box 11)
  - Lord de Freyne and Fritz French to Hamilton Gorges 1854 (Box 11)
- Acts
  - Early Land Tenures 1072-1694, (3 Folders) (Box 11)
  - Act for Commutation 1841 (Box 12)
  - Act for Land Tenure 1842 (Box 12)
  - Act for Land Tenure 1843 (Box 12)
- Stocks
  - Government Stock 1826 (Box 12)
  - Railroad Stock 1846 (Box 12)
  - Transfer of War Stock 1921 (Box 12)
- Wills and Death Statements
  - Family Wills 1419-1912 (Box 12)
  - Henry Gorges 1648 (Box 12)
  - Thomas Baynord 1683 (Box 12)
  - Edward Willes of Dublin, Ireland 1723 (Box 12)
  - Gorges E. Howard 1781 (Box 12)
  - Robert Henry French 1846, 1847 (Box 12)
  - Mary Emily Margaret Mulloy 1920 (Box 12)
  - Statement of Death n.d. (Box 12)
  - Family Wills n.d. (Box 12)
- Other Legal Documents
  - Order 1639 (Box 12)
  - Receipt of Samuel Gorges 1679 (Box 12)
  - Admission 1728 (Box 12)
  - Copyhold Grant 1728 (Box 12)
  - Draft of Surrender 1758 (Box 12)
  - Commissioners of New Streets in Dublin 1762 (Box 12)
  - Survey Map 1795 (Box 12)
  - Copy Recovery 1801 (Box 12)
  - Power of Attorney 1830 (Box 12)
  - Schedule of Incumbrences 1833-1870 (Box 12)
  - Epitome of an Estate 1839-1907 (Box 12)
  - Account 1844 (Box 12)
  - Consent-Rev. John Gorges 1846 (Box 12)
  - List of Papers 1856 (Box 12)
  - Rent Accounts-William D. Kelly 1862-1866 (Box 12)
  - Power of Revocation 1864 (Box 12)
  - Incumbrences 1881 (Box 12)
  - Draft Agreement 1832 (Box 12)
- Historical Information
  - List of Portraits of the Kellys n.d. (Box 12)
  - Gorges Prints n.d. (Box 12)
  - Fascimile of the Magna Carta 1215 (Box 12)
  - History of the Manor of Ashton Philips 1230-1481 (Box 12)
  - Charter of Alianore-Negative 1356 (Box 12)
  - Documents 1356-1437 (Box 13)
  - Monument Inscription 1610-1635 (Box 13)
  - Ghost Story 1714 (Box 13)
  - The Selector or Say's Sunday Reporter 1802 (Box 13)
  - The White Lady, A legend of Artagh 1836 (Box 13)
  - Abbeys 1852 (Box 13)
  - Maine 1879-19_ (Box 13)
  - Monument in Chelsea 1884 (Box 13)
  - Histories of Tuam and County Galway 1887-1891 (Box 13)
  - A Dublin Antiquary of the 17th Centuary 1890 (Box 13)
  - All Saints, Wraxall 1896 (Box 13)
  - Royal Hiberian Academy of Arts 1897 (Box 13)
  - Alleged German Outrages During WWI. 1915 (Box 13)
  - Official Gazette of the Protectorate of South West Africa 1915 (Box 13)
  - "Chelsea, Old Church" 1926 (Box 13)
  - The Essex Rebellion 1929 (Box 13)
  - Old York Transcrpit, Maine 1930 (Box 13)
  - Longford Castle 1931 (Box 13)
  - Account of French Park 1938 (Box 13)
- Research Materials for The Story of a Family Through Eleven Centuries:
  - Notes for Preface n.d. (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Materials n.d. (Box 13)
  - Duplicate References n.d (Box 13)
  - Partial List of Sources Consulted n.d. (Box 13)
  - Photographs, 3 of Gravestones n.d. (Box 13)
  - Materials of No Use n.d. (Box 13)
- Books
  - Gorges Wills and Administrations 1728-1803 (Box 14)
  - A Book on Kilmoon 1761 (Box 14)
  - A Copy of a Book on Kilmoon 1761 (Box 14)
  - Anecdotes of the Gorges Family 1785 (Box 14)
  - The Recollections of Skeffington Gibbon 1796-1829 (Box 14)
  - Account Book 1824 (Box 14)
  - Rev. Brown's Manuscript of the History of the Gorges Family 1250-1701, (7 books) (Box 15)
  - Research Materials n.d. (Box 15)
- Oversize Materials
  - Letter Patent for Kilmoon from James I 1621 Jul 3
  - Photostat Letters, Thomas Gorges 1659
  - Indenture 1797
  - Indenture 1799
  - Agreement, Hamilton Gorges 1803
  - Military Commissions, John Arthur Howard Gorges 1837-1874
  - Extract from Parcels and Schedules 1839 Aug 6
  - Mememorial of an Indenture 1840 Oct 21
  - Memorandum of Agreement for Lease 1843 Feb 2
  - Enfrancisement of Primatestown Estate 1880 Jul 1
  - Appointment of New Trustees 1885 Mar 2
  - Copy of Appointment of New Trustees 1885 Mar 2
  - Genealogy of the Gorges Family n.d.
  - Family Papers n.d.
  - Survey Map n.d.
  - Reference and Valuation of the Estate, Hamilton Gorges 1817
  - Supplemental Abstract 1861
  - Arthur H. Gorges to Richard DuCane et al, Security for 600lv. 1864 Jul 28
  - Supplemental Title to Estate, Manor Kilmoon 1878 Feb 14
  - Broadsides for the Roscommon Militia 1880
  - Mortgage of Reversion of Primatestown Estate 1880 Jul 2
  - Indenture of Primatestown Estate 1880 Jul 2
  - Copy of Indenture for Primatestown Estate 1880 Jul 2
  - Declaration of Trust for Primatestown Estate 1880 Jul 3
  - Deed Poll, H.B. Webster et al to G.H. Bridges 1892 Jul 26
  - Indenture 1892 Jul 26
  - Transfer of a Mortgage on Kilmoon 1892 Jul 26
  - Copy of Indenture 1892 Jul 26
  - Conveyance and Reconveyance, Miss KFC Webster to Mrs. ICG Egerton 1895 Jan 18
  - Broadside Sale of Dublin Property 1906 May 2
  - Reconveyance, Capt. G.H. et al to Mrs. ICG Egerton 1907 Apr 2
  - Conveyance, Mrs. E.G. Webster and Hon. F.W.G. Egerton to Miss K.F.C. Webster 1911
  - Inland Revenue 1920
  - Probate Draft 1920
  - Release and Reassignment of Leaseholdings 1920 Jul 30
  - Draft, Estate of Mrs. Eleanor G. Webster 1921
  - Estate Register 1921 May 17
  - Conveyance, G.H. to Miss K.F.C Webster 1921 Oct 31
  - Conveyance, K.F.C. Webster to Bartle Mooney 1923 Dec 20
  - Allocation Schedule, Estate of Miss K.F.C. Webster 1926 Jan 1
  - Indenture 1618 Aug 15
  - Indenture 1637
  - Indenture 1647
  - Indenture 1659
  - License of Alianation to Susannah Johnston 1758 Aug 26
  - Hamilton Gorges to Patrick Carpenter 1784 May 1
  - Blank Indentures 1800s
  - Indenture 1807
  - Indenture: Hamilton Gorges to Andrew Murphy 1807 Aug 21
  - Map Survey of Kilbrew and Surrounding Areas 1812
  - Indenture 1837
  - Indenture: Hamilton Gorges to Peter Walsh 1837 Aug 21
  - Indenture: H. Gorges to Matthew Collier 1844 Nov 1
  - Indenture: Hamilton Gorges to Matthew Collier 1845
  - City of London Life Assurance Policy 1851 Apr 19
  - Assignment: Susan Louisa Gorges to Edward Tigne 1861 Apr 16
  - Indenture of Manor at Kilmoon 1861 Jun 17
  - Memorial of an Indenture: Manor of Kilmoon 1875 Sep 30
  - Memorial of an Indenture 1878 Feb 14
  - Memorial of an Indenture 1880 Jul 2
  - Memorial of an Indenture 1881 Jun 27
  - Copy of a Memorial of an Indenture 1881 Jun 27
  - Memorial of an Indenture: R. Petch to I.C.G. Egerton 1891 May 16
  - Gorges Family Genealogy n.d
  - Document in Latin n.d.
  - Grave Rubbings n.d.
  - Marriage Agreements: French-Gorges n.d.
  - List of Payments n.d.
  - Indentures and Other Legal Doucments
  - Surrender of Lands at Kilmoon 1758
  - Indenture 1779
  - Kilbrew Indenture Memorial 1832
  - Indenture 1836 Nov 31
  - Admission of Tennents 1861 Jun 17
  - Indenture Settlement 1865 Mar 1
  - Memorial Indenture with List of Payments 1875 Sep 30
  - Indenture 1881 Apr 20
  - Broadsides on Property Sales 1906
  - Indentures n.d.
  - Hamilton Gorges Insurance Policy n.d